<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ameya Godbole</title>
    <link>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ameya Godbole</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Progressively Balanced Multi-class Neural Trees</title>
      <link>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/progressively_balanced_multiclass_neural_trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/progressively_balanced_multiclass_neural_trees/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Prithwijit Guha (Dept. of EEE, IIT Guwahati)
Collaborator: Spoorthy Bhat
This project was my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis at IIT Guwahati.
The basic idea is to allow each node to learn oblique partitions in the input space as opposed to the axis-aligned partitions learned by a standard C4.5 tree. This required the development of a differentiable criterion.
During the course of the project we realized that this hierarchical partitioning results in data-thinning (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Segmentation in Television Stream</title>
      <link>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/commercial_segmentation_in_television_stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/commercial_segmentation_in_television_stream/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Prithwijit Guha (Dept. of EEE, IIT Guwahati)
The problem of detecting when a television stream has switched from content to commercials (advertisements) is difficult because of the wide range of presentation formats available. Even trickier is detecting inter-commercial transitions. Once these transitions are accurately predicted, methods can be developed to further identify the product being advertised. This problem is of importance to companies and advertisers both, as it helps provide credibility to the claimed number times a particular commercial was broadcasted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEep Semantic Kernel (DESK)</title>
      <link>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/desk/</guid>
      <description>Mentors: Dr. Amit Sethi (Dept. of EEE, IIT Bombay), Neeraj K. Vaid
Collaborator: Aman Dalmia
We attempted transfer learning between a convolutional neural network (CNN) in the source domain and maximum margin classifiers in the low-data target domain. Our goal was to leverage the capabilities of the CNN trained on large amounts of training data, especially in image classification tasks, in other tasks with limited data.
The project ongoing at Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quora Question Pairs</title>
      <link>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/quora_question_pairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/quora_question_pairs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bufferless Routeing in Network-On-Chip</title>
      <link>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/bufferless_routeing_in_network_on_chip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/bufferless_routeing_in_network_on_chip/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. John Jose (Dept. of CSE, IIT Guwahati)
Collaborators: Nandan Bedekar, N Hariharan
On-chip interconnection networks are gaining popularity due increase in the number of cores on a processor chip. These networks allow multicore processing without the delays introduced by direct wiring. We modified the network traffic simulator BookSim 2.0 to study the properties of bufferless routers. In particular, we encoded the CHIPPER architecture.
Project repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Intelligent Robot</title>
      <link>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/autonomous_intelligent_robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ameyagodbole.github.io/project/autonomous_intelligent_robot/</guid>
      <description>The Robotics Club of IIT Guwahati developed this project. The aim was to learn on the go which was facilitated through tutorials by senior members of the club and the institute as a whole. The project resulted in a robot that could:
 Map its environment and create a 3D rendering of the world using a stereo-camera (which provided depth information). We later migrated to the Kinect sensor Localize itself in a known map upon initialization Navigate to a given target location (set in the map)  The software was built on top of the Robot Operating System (ROS) which provide packages for handling all the concurrent processes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>